Evan Velasco

1350 E St SE Apt #394, Washington, DC 20003 - (805) 657-5838 - evan.velasco@live.com

Summary

Analyst with over 3 years of experience in advertising technology specializing in extracting business insights from massive datasets. Experience with ad-hoc analysis, ETL, dashboarding, A/B testing, forecasting, and data driven product development. Team player with involvement in several multi-disciplinary projects. Possesses strong knowledge of SQL, Tableau, Domo, and Excel, as well as a working knowledge of Python and R.

Professional Experience

Senior Business Intelligence Analyst

The Washington Post, Washington, DC, April 2022-Present

- Business Intelligence lead for Zeus Technology, an in-house advertising technology company which builds a variety of products including a header bidding wrapper and a self-serve ad buying platform.
- Presented analysis of product performance and assisted in the technical onboarding of new clients.
- Built forecasting models (regression, financial, and product focused) to predict impact of future changes and led analysis measuring the effects of these changes.
- Built new data products such as automated alerting for engineering errors, ad speed reporting, natural language processing model reporting, and granular reporting based on log level data.
- Worked with engineers to build a data backend using Redshift, AWS Athena/S3, and Google BigQuery.

Business Intelligence Analyst

The Washington Post, Washington, DC, April 2021-April 2022

- Managed all analytics for programmatic ad product, providing data and analysis to the sales, product, consumer success, and engineering teams.
- Represented advertising team in A/B test planning and analysis, measuring impact of new technologies and site layout changes.
- Automated programmatic reporting using Excel, Python and Domo, reducing time spent on financial and operational reporting by 30 hours per week and unlocking additional metrics for new insights.
- Built ETL processes in Domo using SQL and Python to feed into new reporting dashboards and forecasts.

Revenue Analyst

Hive Media Group, Carlsbad, CA, August 2019-April 2021

- Analyzed and optimized various channels of programmatic ad revenue including display, native, and video across 20+ sites with over 5 billion ad impressions served monthly.
- Managed analytics and A/B testing for M&A team, completing 3 successful acquisitions and increased revenue by +50% YoY post acquisition.
- Collaborated with product team to design, test, and implement new website layouts which maximized yield.
- Built reporting dashboards in Tableau to analyze ad metrics and lead to actionable strategic initiatives.

Education

University of California San Diego

B.S. Joint Mathematics-Economics, Business Minor

Class of 2019

Skills

- Excel: Lookups, Pivot Tables, Modeling, VBA
- Programming: R, Python, Advanced SQL
- BI: Tableau, Looker, Domo, Google Analytics, Redshift, AWS S3, Snowflake, MySQL, BigQuery
- SQL: Joins, CTEs, Window Functions, Arrays
- Statistics / Machine Learning: A/B Testing,
 Time Series Forecasting, Regression, K-Nearest
 Neighbors, Decision Trees/Random Forest
- Advertising: Google Ad Manager, Programmatic Ad Technology, Supply Side Platform Reporting